Henry Robinson Luce Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1933-1967 (Box 20-70)
  - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Military Strategy Discussion Group, 1958 Correspondents include Henry Kissinger
    - Miscellany, 1936-1966
    - Report to Senate committee, 1959
  - Council on Islamic Affairs, 1956
  - Council on World Tensions See Container 64, World Brotherhood
  - Crusade for Freedom, 1950-1952
  - Dag Hammerskjold Foundation, 1962-1965 (Box 34)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower Library, Abilene, Kans., 1958-1963
  - East and West Association, 1942-1948
  - Economic Club of New York, 1951-1960
  - Economic Cooperation Administration, mission to China, 1948
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1943-1951
  - Fair Employment Practices Commission, 1945-1946
  - Famine Emergency Committee, 1946
  - Far East relief agencies See Container 26, China, Relief agencies
  - Far East-American Council of Commerce and Industry, 1948-1959
  - Farmers Federation Educational and Development Fund, 1935-1952
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America, 1938-1951
  - Fifty Million Fund See also Containers 45-47, National Presbyterian Church, and Container 51, Presbyterians
    - Areas
      - California, 1965-1967
      - Chicago, Ill., 1965-1966
      - Detroit, Mich., 1966-1967
      - Minnesota, 1965-1966
      - Missouri, 1966-1967
      - New Jersey, 1965 (Box 35)
      - New York, 1965-1967
      - Pennsylvania, 1965-1967
    - Contributor correspondence, 1965-1967
    - Gifts and pledges, 1965-1967
    - Major Gifts Committee
      - General correspondence, 1965-1967, (3 folders)
      - Regrets, 1965
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and memoranda, 1965-1967, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Policy and the Westminster Confession, 1965-1966
    - Printed matter, 1965-1967
    - Trips and meetings, 1965-1967
  - Flying Tigers, 1945
  - Fordham University Human Energetics Research, New York, N.Y., 1964
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1948-1955, 1962
  - Foreign Service Educational Foundation, 1943-1945
  - Foundation for Religious Action in Social and Civil Order, 1954-1965, (2 folders) (Box 37)
  - Free China Daily, 1956
  - Free China Fund, 1955, (2 folders)
  - Freedoms Foundation, 1950-1955
  - Friendship House, Scranton, Pa., 1958
  - Fund for Asia, 1956
  - Fund for the Republic See Containers 24-25, Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, and Container 32, Commission on Race and Housing
  - Golden Rule Foundation, circa 1947-1952 For additional material see Container 23, American Mothers Committee
  - Grinnell College, Grinnell, Iowa, 1948-1958 For additional material see Container 100, same heading
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, New York University, New York, N.Y., 1958-1965, (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - Hamilton College, Clinton, N.Y. For additional material see Container 100, same heading
    - General correspondence, 1950-1967, (3 folders)
    - Root Art Center, 1963-1964
  - Hartford Seminary Foundation, Hartford, Conn., 1949-1960
  - Haverford School, Haverford, Pa., 1949-1966
  - Henry Luce Foundation, 1936-1967, (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Herald Tribune Forum, 1954
  - Hotchkiss School, Lakeville, Conn.
    - Building fund, 1944-1951
    - General correspondence, 1937-1966
  - Hungarian relief organizations, 1956-1966
  - India famine relief See Container 24, American Relief for India
  - India League of America, 1944-1959
  - Industrial Areas Foundation, 1949-1950
  - Institute for Philosophical Research, 1955, 1961 (Box 40)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1933-1952 Correspondents include Alfred Kohlberg, (3 folders)
  - International Chamber of Commerce, 1945, 1952
  - International Council of Religious Education, 1949-1950
  - International Courts See Container 53, Rule of Law
  - International Friendship League, 1954
  - International Law Association See Container 53, Rule of Law
  - International Rescue Committee
    - Donovan Commission on Communist Redefection, 1956
    - General correspondence, 1950-1961
  - International University for Social Studies See Container 52, Pro Deo (Box 41)
  - Iron curtain refugees See Container 40, International Rescue Committee
  - Italy, miscellaneous correspondence and memoranda, 1953-1959
  - James Foundation, 1956-1957
  - Japan International Christian University Foundation, 1953-1966
  - Joint Defense Appeal, 1954
  - Junior Chamber of Commerce, Ten Outstanding Young Men, 1949-1950, (2 folders)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, national conference, 1948
  - Kirkland College, Clinton, N.Y., 1964-1966 For additional material see Container 38, Hamilton College
  - Korea Society, 1957-1966
  - Lafayette Fellowship Foundation, 1957-1958
  - Laymen's Movement for a Christian World, 1938-1964 See also Container 52, Religion in American Life, (3 folders) (Box 42)
  - Library of Congress, Clare Boothe Luce Papers, 1956-1958 See also Container 42, Luce, Clare Boothe
  - Limited Editions Club, Art Fellowship, 1936-1939
  - Lone Star Scanner, 1948
  - Los Angeles Independent Publisher, 1948-1949
  - Lotos Club, New York, N.Y., 1937-1961
  - Luce Chapel, Tunghai University, T'ai-chung, Taiwan, 1958-1964
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1963-1967 See also Container 42, Library of Congress, Clare Boothe Luce Papers
  - Luce Foundation See Container 39, Henry Luce Foundation (Box 43)
  - Macalester College, St. Paul, Minn., 1961-1967
  - MacArthur, Douglas See Container 63, Willoughby, Charles A.
  - MacArthur Memorial Foundation, 1963-1966
  - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, New York, N.Y., 1934-1965, (2 folders)
  - Mepkin Abbey, Moncks Corner, S.C., 1959-1960
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, N.Y., 1948-1967, (2 folders)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild, 1933-1955, (2 folders)
  - Monument to Democracy, 1953-1954
  - Museum of Modern Art, New York, N.Y., 1940-1965 (Box 44)
  - National Association of Real Estate Boards See Container 55, Society of Industrial Realtors
  - National Bible Week, 1961-1964
  - National Committee for a Free Europe, 1950-1954 For additional material see Container 33, Crusade for Freedom
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews
    - General correspondence, 1936-1964
    - Reports and research, circa 1964
  - National Council of Churches of Christ, 1951-1965
  - National Football Foundation and Hall of Fame, 1956-1966
  - National Heart Committee, 1948-1950
  - National Information Bureau, 1948-1966
  - National Institute of Social Science, 1948, 1957
  - National Mental Health Program, 1946-1950
  - National Planning Association, 1954-1965
  - National Preparatory School Committee, 1943-1945 (Box 45)
  - National Presbyterian Church, Washington, D.C. See also Containers 34-36, Fifty Million Fund; and Container 51, Presbyterians
    - Architects, 1959-1960 Correspondents include Edward Durell Stone
    - Associates, 1959-1960
    - Background, 1961
    - Brochures, 1957-1966
    - General correspondence, 1957-1961
      - Alphabetical file
        - Hutchinson, Ralph Cooper
        - Ketchum, Inc.
        - Miscellaneous, “A-Z”, (2 folders)
        - Pew, J. Howard, Joseph N., and John G.
      - Chronological file Correspondents include William Culbertson, Edward L.R. Elson, Paul Mellon, Eero Saarinen, Alan M. Scaife, Edward Durell Stone, R. Douglas Stuart, Paul A. Wolfe, and Robert W. Woodruff
        - 1953-1957, (2 folders)
        - 1958-1967, (4 folders) (Box 46)
    - Financial statements, 1957-1962
    - Foundation solicitations, 1960
    - Fund-raising
      - Buffalo, N.Y., 1960
      - California, 1959-1962
      - Chicago, Ill., 1960-1962
      - Indianapolis, Ind., 1959-1960
      - Minneapolis, Minn., 1959-1960
      - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 47)
      - Oklahoma, 1959-1964
      - Pennsylvania, 1958-1960
      - Toledo, Ohio, 1960-1961
    - General Assembly, 1960-1961
    - Gifts to, 1959-1961
    - Meetings, New York, N.Y., and Washington, D.C., 1960 Correspondents include Dwight D. Eisenhower
    - Prospective donors, 1957-1959
    - Southern Presbyterians, 1959
    - Washington, D.C., conferences and dinners, 1961 Correspondents include Dwight D. Eisenhower
    - White House dinner, 1959
  - National Republican Associates, 1959
  - National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students, 1948-1954
  - National Urban League (Box 48)
    - Breakfast, 1951
    - Campaign committee, 1947, (2 folders)
    - Contribution lists, 1947
    - Chronological file
      - 1946
      - 1947
        - Jan.-Mar., (2 folders)
        - Apr.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 49)
      - 1948-1964
    - Editorial by Luce, 1951-1952
    - Form letters, 1947
    - Public relations, 1947
  - National War Fund, 1943-1945
  - Navy League of the United States, 1942-1966
  - Near East College Association, 1946 (Box 50)
  - Newcomen Society in North America, 1956-1966
  - New School for Social Research, New York, N.Y., 1938-1962
  - New York Board of Trade, 1960
  - New York Chamber of Commerce, 1949-1964
  - New York Heart Association, 1951-1953, 1958
  - New York State Civil Defense Commission, New York State Defense Council, 1959-1962, (3 folders)
  - New York Stock Exchange Anniversary, 1967
  - New York University, New York, N.Y.
    - Gallatin Associates, 1957-1959
    - Hall of Fame for Great Americans See Container 38, same heading
  - New York World's Fair, New York, N.Y., 1960-1961
  - New York Zoological Society, 1941-1950
  - Occidental College, Los Angeles, Calif., 1957-1965 For additional material see Container 100, same heading
  - Operation Brotherhood See Container 40, International Rescue Committee
  - Overseas School of Rome, Rome, Italy, 1953-1956
  - Oxford University, Oxford, England See Container 31, Christ Church (Box 51)
  - Pacific War Memorial, 1947-1948
  - Paramount Pictures, 1933-1941, (2 folders)
  - Partisan Review, 1951-1961 Correspondents include Allen Grover and William Phillips
  - Philippines, Japanese attack See Container 63, Willoughby, Charles A.
  - Phoenix, Ariz.
    - Art museum, 1958-1966
    - Symphony Guild, 1967
  - Pilgrims of the United States, 1949-1953
  - Politics
    - Connecticut, 1952
    - “Eisenhower-Nixon Bandwagon,” 1952 Correspondents include Mason Rossiter Smith
    - Presidential campaign, 1952 For additional material see Container 47, National Republican Associates
  - Presbyterians See also Containers 34-36, Fifty Million Fund, and Containers 45-47, National Presbyterian Church
    - Fund-raising, 1938-1963
    - Presbyterian Life, 1943-1947
    - Presbyterian Progress Foundation, 1963-1964
    - Presbyterian Study Paper on China, 1967 (Box 52)
    - Presbyterian Tribune, 1936-1956
  - Prescott College, Prescott, Ariz., 1963-1965 Correspondents include Barry M. Goldwater
  - Preservation of Camelback Mountain, Maricopa, Ariz., 1965-1966 Correspondents include Barry M. Goldwater For additional material see Container 62, Valley Beautiful Citizens
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J., Dulles Library, 1959-1964
  - Pro Deo
    - American Council for International Promotion of Democracy under God, 1962-1965
    - International University for Social Studies, Rome, Italy, 1953-1966
  - Project Pakistan-India-Ceylon, 1953-1954
  - Protestant Council of New York, 1949-1963 For additional material see Container 42, Laymen's Movement
  - “Protestant World,” 1950
  - Religion in American Life, 1949-1963 See also Container 42, Laymen's Movement
  - Robert A. Taft Institute of Government, New York, N.Y., 1964
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund Special Studies, 1956-1961 Correspondents include Townsend Hoopes, Henry Kissinger, Laurence S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller (Box 53)
  - Roosevelt Hospital, New York, N.Y.
    - Contributions, 1948-1966
    - General, 1937-1956, (2 folders)
  - Rule of Law
    - Correspondence and memoranda
      - Dulles, John Foster, and Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1958
      - General, 1955-1966, (2 folders)
    - Dinner, 1960 (Box 54)
    - Gifts of The People and the Court by Charles L. Black, 1960
    - International Law Association, 1957-1958
    - Repeal of Connally Amendment, 1959-1963
    - Southwestern Legal Foundation and Robert Storey, 1957-1967
    - World Peace Through Law Center and Charles S. Rhyne, 1958-1967
  - Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., 1949
  - Saint John's College, Annapolis, Md., and Santa Fe, N.M., 1966
  - Saint Louis University and Spirit of St. Louis awards, St. Louis, Mo., 1955-1966
  - Saint Mary's College, Notre Dame, Ind., 1951-1965
  - Save the Children Federation, 1948-1965 (Box 55)
  - School textbooks, 1951
  - Science and religion, 1962
  - Society of American Historians, 1949-1951
  - Society of Industrial Realtors, 1951-1953
  - Spence-Chapin Adoption Service, 1947-1966
  - Springfield College, Springfield, Mass., 1961-1965 For additional material see Container 101, same heading
  - Ssu-tu, Chiao (artist), 1946-1947
  - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif., 1948-1963, (2 folders)
  - Strip mining research, 1966 (Box 56)
  - Trinity College, Hartford, Conn., 1964-1965
  - Tunghai University, T'ai-chung shih, Taiwan See Container 42, Luce Chapel
  - Union Theological Seminary, New York, N.Y., 1944-1966, (2 folders)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia (formerly Associated Boards for Christian Colleges in China, circa 1932-1947, and United Board for Christian Colleges in China, circa 1947-1960)
    - 1935-1946, (5 folders)
    - 1947-1956, (8 folders) (Box 57)
    - 1957-1965, (4 folders) (Box 58)
  - United China Relief See also Containers 60-62, United Service to China
    - Auchincloss, Douglas, 1941-1943
    - Dispute with American Board of Medical Aid to China, 1943-1944 Correspondents include Alfred Kohlberg
    - Fund-raising, by cities, 1941-1943, (2 folders) (Box 59)
    - General
      - 1941-1942, (5 folders)
      - 1943-1945, (3 folders) (Box 60)
    - Report on UCR and China Institute, 1945
  - United Christmas Appeal for China, 1940
  - United Church Canvas, 1948
  - United Community Campaign of America, 1955-1966
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1950
  - United Service Organization, 1942, 1959-1960
  - United Service to China See also Containers 58-60, United China Relief
    - “Airlift of the Spirit” layout, 1949
    - Chronological file (Box 61)
      - 1946-1949, (6 folders)
      - 1950-1958, (2 folders) (Box 62)
  - United States Churchill Foundation, 1964-1966
  - University of the Andes, Bogota, Columbia, 1958-1960
  - Valley Beautiful Citizens Council, Phoenix, Ariz., 1963-1965
  - Vergilian Society, 1953-1963, (2 folders)
  - Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass., 1947-1955
  - Westminster College, Fulton, Mo.
    - Churchill, Winston
      - Memorial Correspondents include Anthony Montague Brown, John M. Dalton, Patrick Hornsbrugh, and Harry S. Truman
        - 1961-1963
        - 1964-1967 (Box 63)
      - Ninetieth Birthday Dinner, 1964, (2 folders)
  - WICC-TV, Bridgeport, Conn., 1952
  - William Allen White Foundation, University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kans., 1950-1963
  - William Morrow and Co., 1936-1939
  - Willoughby, Charles A., military intelligence reports, 1945
    - “The Destruction of Manila”
    - “MacArthur's Campaigns”
    - “The Return of MacArthur”
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1959 (Box 64)
  - Wooster, College of, Wooster, Ohio, 1962-1967, (3 folders)
  - World Brotherhood, 1951-1965
  - World Council of Churches, 1948-1966
  - World literacy, 1952
  - World Peace Through Law Center See Container 53, Rule of Law (Box 65)
  - World Trade Advisory Committee, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1957-1959, (2 folders)
  - World Trade Foundation of America, 1945-1947
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn. For additional material see Container 101, same heading
    - Alumni activities, 1935-1966
    - Art exhibitions, donations, 1937-1962
    - Athletic Association, 1933-1948, 1956
    - Catholic center, 1962-1963
    - Class of 1920, 1935-1965
    - Council, 1948-1966
    - Day, George Parmly, 1937-1947 (Box 66)
    - Institute of International Studies, 1943-1950, (2 folders)
    - Keller, Albert G., 1937-1943
    - Letters of recommendation, 1944-1950
    - Library, 1951-1966
    - Literary magazine, 1935-1966
    - Luce Professorship of Jurisprudence
      - Correspondence, 1955-1962
      - Financial records, 1955-1961
    - Miscellaneous correspondence
      - 1937-1956
      - 1957-1966 (Box 67)
    - Pierson College, 1941-1955, 1965-1966
    - Program for the Arts and Sciences, 1961-1963
    - Review of Metaphysics, 1947-1964 Correspondents include Robert Thom and Paul Weiss, (2 folders)
    - Visits to colleges, 1935-1939, 1965
    - Yale Daily News, 1935-1966
  - Yale-in-China Association
    - Correspondence, 1941-1966
    - Printed reports, minutes, and related material, 1937-1965, (3 folders) (Box 68)
    - Rebuilding Committee
      - Contribution lists, 1947-1954
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1945-1954 Correspondents include Luther A. Weigle and Reginald W. Wheeler
        - Members, 1947 Correspondents include Thornton Wilder (Box 69)
        - Solicitations, 1947-1948
      - Harriman, Averell, committee, 1947-1948
  - Yeamans Hall Club, Charleston, S.C., 1936-1961, (2 folders)
  - Years of the Modern, 1948
  - Yenching University, Peking, China
    - Correspondence, 1933-1948
    - Printed reports, minutes, and related material, 1932-1954
  - YMCA (Box 70)
    - Contributions and miscellaneous matters, 1935-1963
    - Mahaska Center, Oskaloosa, Iowa, 1966-1967
- Speeches and Writings File, 1928-1967 (Box 70-83)
  Speeches and articles with related correspondence and attachments, drafts and final copies of speeches, and memoirs and notes.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Chronological file (Box 70)
    - 1928-1967, index to speeches and articles
    - 1928-1945, miscellaneous speeches and notes
    - 1933, “Indispensable Men,” University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill.
    - 1936, “Education and Aristocracy,” University of Chattanooga, Chattanooga, Tenn.
    - 1937, “When I was in college... ,” Yale Club, Montclair, N.J.
    - 1939, “Education As an Inheritance,” Haverford School Alumni
    - 1940, foreword to Why England Slept, John F. Kennedy
    - 1941
      - Mar., “Since the Constitution... ,” China Colleges luncheon
      - Apr.
        - “I'm glad as always... ,” Advertising Club, Cleveland, Ohio
        - “Most news travels... ,” Book and Author luncheon
      - June
        - “At the outset... ,” Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, Calif.
        - “A few weeks... ,” United China Relief Dinner, New York, N.Y.
        - “My trip to China... ,” United China Relief Dinner, Chicago, Ill.
        - “One year ago... ,” Radio WABC and network (Box 71)
        - “Writing during the last... ,” Brooks School Prize Day
      - July
        - “May I at the outset... ,” Buffalo Museum, Buffalo, N.Y.
      - Oct.
        - “The Future,” New York Junior League
        - “I am particularly... ,” Automobile Manufacturers
      - Nov.
        - “Many Americans are... ,” New York Presbytery
        - “Most of you seem... ,” Sunday Breakfast Club
        - “One of the most... ,” Foreign Policy Association
      - Dec., “One of the most... ,” United China Relief Dinner, Los Angeles, Calif.
    - 1942
      - Feb., “Writing during the last... ,” Yale Daily News dinner
      - Apr., “Just a year ago... ,” Chamber of Commerce, Rochester, N.Y.
      - May, “Some weeks ago... ,” Grinnell College, Grinnell, Iowa
      - Dec., “For at least two years... ,” St. Thomas Church, New York, N.Y.
    - 1943
      - Jan.
        - “Any of us who... ,” United War Fund Campaign
        - Remarks, YMCA Council and Board
      - June, “There is one question... ,” commencement address, Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio
    - 1944 (Box 72)
      - Mar., “In his book... ,” Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, New York, N.Y.
      - June, “A New Measure of Patriotism,” YMCA dinner
      - July
        - “The Human Situation,” Stanford University, Stanford, Calif.
        - “I hope you are... ,” China-American Council dinner
      - Dec., “The World's Need for a Church,” Immanuel Congregational Church, Hartford, Conn.
    - 1946
      - Feb., “The Ethical Problems Facing America,” Duke University, Durham, N.C.
      - Sept., “The Christianity of the Missionary,” San Francisco Opera House, San Francisco, Calif.
    - 1946-1947, miscellaneous speeches and notes
    - 1947
      - Jan., “The Church,” Church Federation of Chicago, Chicago, Ill.
      - Feb., “Ministers of the Gospel... ,” New York State Pastors
      - Mar., “The New Age of the Church,” The Christian Century (Box 73)
      - May
        - Foreword, How the Church Grows, Roy A. Burkhart
        - Speech notes, YMCA Fund luncheon
      - June, speech notes, Friendship House, Scranton, Pa.
    - 1948
      - May
        - “In the last few years... ,” Interracial Fellowship Meeting
        - “One Sunday last winter... ,” Union Theological Seminary Alumni
      - Sept., “If I have any... ,” Colgate University, Colgate, N.Y.
      - Nov.
        - Broadcast, “Voice of America”
        - “Christian Responsibility,” United Council of Church Women
      - Dec., “I owe you thanks... ,” Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Va.
    - 1949
      - Mar., remarks, interdenominational group
      - Nov., remarks, Laymen's Movement
      - Dec., “Every now and again... ,” Interseminary Conference
    - 1950
      - Feb., “The Guide to Peace,” National Conference of Christians and Jews
      - Mar., “One of the most... ,” United Congregational Church, Bridgeport, Conn. (Box 74)
    - 1951
      - Apr.
        - “Two months ago... ,” St. George's Society, New York, N.Y.
        - “We heard this morning.. .” (Justice Holmes speech), American Bar Association
      - Oct., “An invitation to come... ,” College of Idaho, Caldwell, Idaho
      - Dec., “Religions in America Today,” National Conference of Christians and Jews Brotherhood Dinner
    - 1952 (Box 75)
      - June
        - “Members of the class... ,” Lafayette College, Easton, Pa.
        - “Victory through Law,”American Bar Association
        - “Victory through Law,” Pennsylvania Bar Association
      - Oct.
        - “The University As Prophet,” inauguration ceremony, Trinity College, San Antonio, Tex.
        - “I want to talk to you... ,” Michigan Bar Association
      - Nov., “The Mind of the Church,” Christian Church Dinner
    - 1953
      - Jan., remarks, American Friends of the Middle East
      - Apr., “Peace in Our Time,” Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, New York, N.Y.
      - June, “The Great Liberal Tradition,” Temple University, Philadelphia, Pa.
      - Nov., “The American Proposition,” International University for Social Studies (Pro Deo), Rome, Italy
    - 1954
      - Apr., remarks, Presbyterian Men's Club, Rye, N.Y.
      - May, “Representative Men,” Yale Alumni, Cleveland, Ohio (Box 76)
      - June, “The Adventure of Ideas,” Occidental College, Los Angeles, Calif.
    - 1955
      - Nov.
        - “The Public Philosophy and the Spirit of Geneva,” St. Louis University, St. Louis, Mo.
        - Remarks, Yale Club, New York, N.Y.
    - 1956
      - June, speech notes, Jewish Theological Seminary luncheon
      - Oct., “Peace Is the Work of Justice,” Connecticut Bar Association, (2 folders)
    - 1957
      - Mar., “God of Our Fathers,” Lake Forest College, Lake Forest, Ill.
      - Sept., “A Big Year for the Law,” Indiana Bar Association (Box 77)
      - Oct., “A Big Year for the Law,” Nebraska Bar Association
      - Nov., “God in His Church,” Westminster Presbyterian Church, Scranton, Pa.
    - 1958
      - Jan., “A journalist has... ,” University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pa.
      - Apr., “It is a great joy... ,” Yale Daily News Eightieth Anniversary Dinner
      - Sept., “The Meaning of the Rule of Law,” Missouri Bar Association
    - 1959
      - Feb., “The Way of the Law,” Fellows of the American Bar
      - Apr., “Three weeks ago... ,” International Chamber of Commerce